[The Heir]
[Episode 21]
Manager Shao,
when are the delivery dates?
Is there still time to remake them?
Most of them are due soon.
The earliest order is due tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I have only managed household affairs,
without knowing anything about business.
Regarding the ink orders, Zhen,
what do you think we should do?
I saw Doggie and the others
sort out some boxes of ink sticks
that hadn't been burned by the fire.
They are perfectly intact inside and out.
Should we use them
to fulfill tomorrow's order first?
No.
Once exposed to high heat,
the ink can crack easily.
It might look intact on the surface,
but it's actually unusable.
Our Li Ink can lose anything,
but not our reputation.
Manager Zhen, you're right.
I was anxious and didn't think it through.
For these recent ink orders,
follow the contracts
and pay the penalty in full.
Also, Manager Shao,
please help me arrange a meeting
with the ink merchants.
Let's discuss with them
whether we can give up 30% of the profit
to delay the delivery dates
for a few days.
Okay.
I got it.
How is everything going
at the ink workshop?
Besides the smoke shed,
is there any damage elsewhere?
Besides the smoke shed and warehouse,
the rest isn't seriously damaged.
It should be usable
with some minor repairs.
That's good.
Eldest Aunt,
I once learned ink-making for 3 years
at the Li family's old ink workshop.
It might be decrepit,
but it still works fine.
Before the smoke shed is repaired,
let's move
the lampblack-making process there.
That's not a problem.
It's just that...
Just what?
It's just that the upcoming deliveries are
all large ink orders.
There are
about 10,000 ink sticks in total.
If we compensate them all,
the funds on the ink workshop's books
are far from enough, I'm afraid.
With my previous wages
and the revenue
from the New Li Ink Workshop
combined,
there should be 500 taels of silver.
Take it for now.
I'll figure out a way for the rest.
I still have my dowry.
If I take out my entire dowry,
it'll cover 1,000 taels of silver.
Eldest Aunt.
Eldest Young Lady, how can we do this?
A woman's dowry
is her lifeblood.
Zhen is right.
Our Li family can lose anything,
except for the reputation of Li Ink.
We won't short them a single penny
of the compensation we owe.
Follow the contracts.
At a time like this,
we must work together to pull through.
Eldest Aunt,
Li Ink will surely
get through this crisis.
I promise you
I will definitely
earn back your dowry, Eldest Aunt,
without a single penny missing.
I believe in you.
This whole thing started
because of us, the Sixth Branch.
So, of course, we should cover part of it.
Third Aunt.
Sister-in-law,
are you distancing yourselves from us,
the Sixth Branch,
because of Jingdong's mistake?
Why did you keep
such a serious issue from us?
Ying is right.
We bear unforgivable blame for this.
Even if we have to pay compensation,
we should be the ones to pay it first.
You have all misunderstood.
Given Jingdong's current state,
how could I, as your sister-in-law,
cause you any more trouble?
You've got that wrong, Eldest Aunt.
We are a family.
Now that Li Ink is in trouble,
we should face it together.
There is no such thing as causing trouble.
Sister-in-law,
my dowry isn't as substantial as yours,
but
if I add up the jewelry I've saved
over the years,
it should be worth
a few hundred taels of silver.
Early tomorrow morning,
I will tally up the revenue
from the estate.
It should be around a few hundred taels
of silver as well.
I have some, too.
Unfortunately,
I spent it all on pills and talismans.
I-I will sell them all tomorrow.
That should fetch
about 100 taels of silver.
Manager Shao, please calculate it.
Is this enough now?
It's about enough.
Probably enough.
Great.
Wonderful.
Give this
to Shao An.
Okay.
Thank you, Grandpa.
Mother?
Zhen.
Send this to him as well.
Over the years,
I've held a grudge against the Li family.
But the Li family is,
after all, the roots
of your father and grandfather.
Besides, since I married
into the Li family,
your Seventh Grandmother
has treated me well.
I must return this favor.
You've waited for me this long.
You must have something to tell me, right?
I heard about the fire
at the ink workshop.
And those merchants who signed contracts
and placed ink orders
are making a scene,
demanding an explanation from Li Ink.
And Zhen, now that you've taken over
the position of its manager,
it seems that you can't avoid
dealing with the whole mess.
Thank you for telling me that.
But besides this,
you actually
want to talk about something else, right?
You want
to withdraw your shares.
Why do you always assume
that I want to withdraw my shares?
Instead of withdrawing,
I'm indeed adding more.
I call this taking advantage of a crisis
to increase my investment
in the Li family.
You have already helped me a lot.
I can't owe you anymore.
What do you mean by owing?
I told you,
I'm taking advantage of a crisis.
Come on, do you think I'm a fool?
You think if you put it that way,
I'll feel at ease accepting it?
Zhen,
since I chose to cooperate
with you and the Li family,
of course,
I am willing to add more funds
to help Li Ink tide over the difficulties.
Thank you for your kindness, Master Qi.
But in the end,
this is an internal matter
for the Li family to solve.
So I won't trouble you.
Alright.
Then just let me know
if anything comes up.
Eldest Young Lady, Third Young Lady.
Manager Shao,
have those ink merchants
who caused trouble been dealt with?
It's all settled.
Thanks to Manager Zhen's advance planning,
before those head managers
could even make a fuss,
they received their full compensation.
As they left,
they kept praising Li Ink's staff
for being considerate,
ethical, and trustworthy.
They said
once the ink workshop is fully repaired,
they'd come back to place more ink orders.
Manager Shao!
Manager Zhen.
You are really fast on your feet.
I couldn't keep up with you,
even though I hurried.
Look at me.
I just wanted to report
the good news as soon as possible.
Excuse my manners.
It's fine. I'm just teasing you.
Eldest Aunt, Third Aunt.
Eldest Young Lady, Third Young Lady,
Lord Yan sent someone with a message.
Masters,
the Tribute Ink selection is approaching.
Lord Yan has decided that in 2 days,
the ink worship ceremony
will be held by the Xin'an River.
[To Li Ink Workshop,
the Tribute Ink selection is near.]
[The ink worship ceremony
will be held by Xin'an River in 2 days.]
All participating ink workshops are
requested to arrive on time for it
[All participating ink workshops are
requested to arrive on time for it.]
and submit their participation document.
Those who arrive late
will be disqualified
from the Tribute Ink selection.
Thank you.
Mr. Zhou, please see him out.
This way, please.
Zhen.
You are now the manager of Li Ink.
You should be the one to decide.
Eldest Aunt, regarding the Tribute Ink,
it involves
Uncle Jingdong's painstaking effort.
Let's wait until he wakes up.
Mother!
Father is awake! He is awake!
Father, you're awake!
Jingdong.
Be careful.
Take it easy.
Jingdong, you're finally awake.
You really scared everyone!
It's good that you're awake.
Why did you save me?
Father!
Jingdong, what are you doing?
Go away!
What are you doing?
Let me die!
Jingdong!
Master!
Let me die!
Father!
Can you stop messing around?
Let me die!
-Father!
-Jingdong!
Let me die!
If you die, what will Zhengshen and I do?
I don't deserve to live.
Why did you save...
Go away!
Jingdong!
Let me die!
Zhengshen!
Carry your father
and come with me!
Zhen, what are you going to do?
Doesn't he want to die?
Fine.
I'll find him a good place to die.
What...
Carry him!
Let me go!
Where are you taking me?
Zhengshen, put your father here.
Put him down.
Father.
Zhen,
why did you bring me here?
Aren't you determined to die?
Fine!
Today,
in front of the Sixth Master,
smash your head against this coffin
and die.
I promise
no one will dare to stop you.
The Sixth Master died for Li Ink.
Even before he died,
he still cared about the family's honor.
Today,
I'll let him see clearly
how the son
he sacrificed his life to protect
gives up over a little setback
and attempts suicide
over personal gains and losses!
But before you die,
you must know one thing.
The fire you set
burned everything to the ground.
You burned
more than half of the warehouse!
None of the ink orders
the Li family took can be delivered.
Do you know
where we got the compensation money?
We got it from the dowries of Eldest Aunt
and Third Aunt,
Aunt Chunhua's estate revenue,
New Li Ink Workshop's income,
Manager Shao's half-year salary,
and the personal savings
of my grandfather and mother.
Even Zhengshen
sold his precious golden pills
and talismans!
The whole family barely
scraped together enough money.
Li Ink's century-old foundation
was almost reduced to ashes by a fire.
But in the entire Li family,
from the Sixth Master who died for Li Ink
to everyone who's given it their all
and supported each other
through hard times,
no one is a coward!
Only you, Li Jingdong,
gave up easily over a minor setback
and tried to escape it all through death.
You're a coward.
You are so weak!
You think death can end all the pain.
But have you ever
thought about your family?
Your wife
and your son,
what should they do?
Third Aunt has been
crying every day because of you.
Zhengshen rushed
into the fire alone to save you
and burned one of his arms.
Do you really want them to feel guilty,
blame themselves, and live in regret
for the rest of their lives
because of your death?
Ask yourself.
Do you truly feel no shame?
Uncle Jingdong,
after hearing what I said,
if you still want to die,
no one can stop you.
Your life is
yours to decide.
Father.
L-Let's go back.
Zhengshen...
Where did you get burned?
Let me check on you.
I'm fine.
Let me see.
It's nothing.
Show me.
Does it hurt?
It doesn't, Father.
Sorry, I've made you
and your mother suffer.
I apologize
to both of you.
Father.
Get up, Jingdong.
Ying.
Jingdong,
since you returned from the capital,
crippled
and broken in spirit,
I've been waiting day and night.
I've been waiting for you to recover
and pull yourself together.
I've waited for the whole 13 years
for you to sober up.
If you really leave us behind,
I will never let you go
in this life, even if I
have to chase you to the underworld!
It's my fault. I was wrong.
[Li Ink]
Uncle Jingdong,
do you still want to die today?
I've already died once.
I can't die again.
Zhen,
I came here specifically to wait for you.
After I woke up,
Zhengshen
told me everything
that had happened in the past few days.
You were right to scold me.
Well scolded.
Your words woke me up
and brought me,
a useless wreck, back to life.
Uncle Jingdong, what are you doing?
Get up quickly. Come on.
Zhen,
for all these years,
I have treated you harshly
on various occasions.
I owe you an apology.
I was wrong.
I made you suffer.
When the Li family
was struck by a disaster,
I should have been the one
to support the family.
But I complained about everything,
dwelled on my resentment,
and left this whole mess to you.
You were the one
who supported this family in my place.
On behalf of the Sixth Branch
and the Li family,
thank you.
It's all in the past.
It's over now.
Come on.
Sit down, please.
Fate is cruel.
Your father,
Jingyuan, and Jingqi,
were
far superior to me
in both talent and character.
Yet I am the one who survived.
I failed to support this family for them
or secure this business.
I let them down.
Uncle Jingdong,
you can't say that.
The past few days,
I've visited all the regular clients
of Li Ink.
They all praised us,
saying the quality of our ink is stable,
and the delivery dates
have never been delayed.
Over the years,
you have been overseeing the ink delivery.
You have supported this family very well.
Not at all.
I know exactly what I am capable of.
Everyone has their own expertise.
To maintain an ink workshop,
relying solely on ink-making is
absolutely not enough.
You also need
to deal with those ink merchants.
In the past few days,
as the acting manager of the family,
I have already seen
how unfathomable the business realm is.
So, Uncle Jingdong,
don't underestimate yourself.
Now,
the Tribute Ink selection is approaching.
During the few days you were in a coma,
Eldest Aunt handed this matter
over to me to decide.
But I know
you've put years of effort into it
through countless bitter winters
and scorching summers.
So, regarding this matter,
I can't make the decision on your behalf.
[Invitation to the Ink Worship Ceremony]
Lord Yan is holding
the ink worship ceremony.
Has the Li family decided
whether to participate or not?
I don't know either.
But I guess
they will.
Li Ink has suffered disasters
over and over again,
and it's a troubled time.
Under such circumstances,
if she still holds on without withdrawing,
then Zhen really has guts.
It is precisely because
of the repeated blows Li Ink has suffered
and their low morale
that I guess she will participate.
This is exactly the perfect time
to get everyone in Li Ink united as one.
You really know her well.
Sister.
Fine.
I won't tease you anymore.
The invitation
to the Chen family's ink testing event?
I heard that the Chen family
also has a peerless ink this time
to participate
in the Tribute Ink selection.
So, Sister,
as long as we invest
in both the Li and Chen Ink Workshops,
[Dear Madam Wang]
[From Chen Ink, Chen Jiru]
our chances of winning will be greater.
This way, it won't delay
the important military supplies.
So I'd like to ask you, Sister,
to invest in the Chen family
in your name.
I will pay for it.
You've considered it
quite thoroughly.
Okay, don't worry.
I will do my best.
But if we do this,
how will you explain it to Li Ink?
It's my duty.
I believe Li Zhen will understand me.
It's just that
she will be under more pressure.
[The memorial tablet
of my late father, Li Jinhe]
Today is an auspicious day.
We set up an altar for ink worship.
Anyone wishing to participate
in the Tribute Ink selection
must present the document
and bow to the Founder's Black Banner.
[Li Ink's Participation Document
for the Tribute Ink]
No one
from the Li family is participating.
It is considered a withdrawal.
I hereby announce
that it is now the auspicious time!
Start the funeral procession!
Father!
Please rest in peace!
Lift the coffin!
Hold on, Lord Yan!
Please hold on, Lord Yan.
The auspicious time hasn't arrived.
Please wait a moment, Lord Yan.
Master Qi, what do you mean by this?
It is currently the Xinwei hour.
Xin represents Yin Gold,
and Wei represents Yin Earth.
Xinwei means Earth generates Gold.
Mutual generation is auspicious.
It is indeed the auspicious hour.
You're right, Lord Yan.
From heaven's perspective,
the Xinwei hour is an auspicious time.
But for the ink, it is not.
You are here today
for ink worship.
And the ink's element is Water.
But the Xinwei hour
contains an element of Earth.
Earth restrains Water.
Mutual restraint is dangerous
and detrimental to the ink.
I hold the view
that the Renshen hour is
the true auspicious time.
Besides, Lord Yan,
the Tribute Ink selection is
of great significance.
I said this
in the hope that the ink worship ceremony
could be timed
and executed perfectly.
I hope you will think twice, Lord Yan.
Master Qi has got a point.
Then everyone from the ink workshops and I
will wait here for a while?
Thank you for considering things
for the Huizhou ink industry, Lord Yan.
My Lord, the Xinwei ink worship
was specifically calculated
by some fortune-teller
hired by the Literary Association.
You can't trust
Qi Jiu's one-sided claim.
Just now, every family
has presented their documents.
If the ink worship ceremony is delayed
or interrupted again,
I'm afraid the Founding Master
will be offended.
Lord Yan.
It is the auspicious time!
Beat the drums!
Bow!
Kneel!
Prostrate!
Rise!
The ceremony is complete!
The Li family is late, sorry.
Lord Yan,
today is my father's funeral. So we're
late as the Li family's participants.
Please,
forgive us, my lord.
In this case,
the Li family doesn't intend to withdraw
from the Tribute Ink selection, huh?
Indeed.
Li Ink will participate.
That's what I've been waiting for.
Li Ink
treats ink
with utmost passion and sincerity.
Despite myriad difficulties,
you will never back down.
Bow!
Kneel!
Prostrate!
Rise!
Bow!
The ceremony is complete!
Uncle Jingdong,
I've placed all your unburnt ink clumps
right here for you.
Manager Shao and Zhengshen
helped gather them.
Have a seat.
Okay.
These are all useless things.
Thank you for your hard work.
Using almonds as a preservative
and adding borneol for fragrance,
what a good idea.
This ink is truly great.
Zhen,
I only knew before
that you were very talented in ink-making.
I didn't expect you to have reached
the level of knowing the components
just by smelling.
I was thinking,
perhaps we should use Fu Jin Ink
for the Tribute Ink selection.
It has already gained a reputation
and cured Lord Yan's daughter.
Uncle Jingdong,
my Fu Jin Ink is a medicinal ink.
It might not be suitable
for the Tribute Ink selection.
Besides,
you've put so much effort
into this pine soot ink.
How can you give up halfway?
Let's refine it together.
I believe it will definitely
turn out even better.
Zhen,
take this.
What's this?
This is the ink recipe
for top-grade pine soot ink
collected by us, the Sixth Branch.
By longstanding family rules,
the ink recipe must not be passed
to outsiders.
It is the foundation
of the ink workshop's survival.
Uncle Jingdong,
after all,
I haven't returned to the clan yet.
This is inappropriate.
If I say it's appropriate, then it is.
Since you've let go of past grudges,
how can I still be selfish?
Besides,
this ink recipe
has become my inner demon,
doing me more harm than good.
If you can draw inspiration from it
and add brilliance to the new ink,
that would be a great blessing for Li Ink.
If your Seventh Grandmother were awake,
she would definitely support my decision.
I promise I will
give it my all.
[Ink-Mixing Area]
Please give it to me, sir.
Come on, look.
Didn't he just sweep it?
Now there's none left.
Put it back on again.
No, it's still too thin.
Make it thicker.
T-This isn't that hard.
It's pretty much like making pills.
Shut up,
or I'll hit you with my cane.
Dad, I'll go practice ink-mixing again.
I'll go practice it.
You can keep burning.
The oil soot hasn't stopped yet.
Uncle Jingdong,
I think we succeeded.
Miss Li Zhen, Master,
the Chen family sent an invitation
to the ink testing event,
saying they've finalized
the ink for submission.
Qi Jiu,
Cuiqiao is also here.
Did she invest in Chen Ink?
Yes.
I asked her to do it.
Doing business needs
to play both sides sometimes.
It's just a deal. Just for business.
This ink is indeed brilliant.
This ink is bright but not gaudy,
with distinct layers.
The lingering charm
is indescribable.
Third Master Chen,
your Chen family successfully produced
this lacquer-soot ink
of such an extraordinary quality
before the Tribute Ink selection.
It's truly not easy.
You flatter us, my lord.
We're flattered.
Master Li.
My lord.
Come here.
Check out this lacquer-soot ink
from the Chen family.
See which one is better
compared to your Li family's
ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Yes.
My lord,
this ink...
Hui Ink has not been listed
among all the trades since ancient times,
but it holds a high status.
All matters in the ink industry are always
managed by the Literary Association.
Master ink makers are also scholars.
And in literature,
there is no absolute first place.
The same goes for ink.
I think,
for every master ink maker,
the ink they make themselves
must rank first in their hearts.
Just as the ancient lacquer-soot ink
of the Li family
definitely ranks first in the hearts
of Uncle Jingdong and me.
Am I right, Uncle Jingdong?
And this piece of ink from the Chen family
must also be the first in the hearts
of Third Grandfather Chen
and Uncle Junshan.
Third Grandfather,
does what I say make sense?
Yes, it makes sense.
What an eloquent girl!
Lord Yan,
Third Master Chen,
since everyone is so interested
in this Cloud Ink,
can we try this ink ourselves
to see its brilliance?
What do you think, Third Master Chen?
You are all peers in the ink industry.
Please feel free to give it a try.
It's my honor.
Thank you, Third Master Chen.
Please.
Clouds gather around the sun.
The ink lives up to its name.
Its color is as deep as the night,
and its luster is as smooth as jade.
Nice ink.
It's really amazing ink.
Eldest Young Master Tian,
then I would also like to ask
when I will have the honor to see
the Tian family's ink for submission?
Lord Yan,
this is the newly made Styrax Ink
from the Tian family,
which we intend
to submit for the Tribute Ink selection.
Please evaluate it, my lord.
[Styrax]
Third Master Chen.
Madam Wang.
Eldest Young Master Tian,
forgive me for being blunt.
One of the standards
for an excellent ink stick is
a pure scent.
This ink
has a vulgar scent
and is made from complicated materials.
Compared to the Chen family's Cloud Ink,
it is inferior, I'm afraid.
You are absolutely right, my lord.
The Chen Ink has such a profound heritage.
Our Tian family's Styrax Ink
only looks good on the surface,
but it's nowhere near good enough.
I am so ashamed.
Zhen,
Tian Benchang is a cunning man.
I guess the Styrax Ink he brought out
at the ink testing event just now was
just a distraction.
Given Tian Benchang's tricks,
he definitely has a backup plan.
Zhen,
although I don't know how to make ink,
I have...
still evaluated various inks.
The Chen family's Cloud Ink we saw
at the ink testing event just now
was truly out of my expectations,
showing great momentum to win.
Are you really
not going to submit the Fu Jin Ink
for the selection?
In my opinion,
the Fu Jin Ink
can only represent me personally.
Yet the pine soot ink is
the ink
that can truly represent the Li family.
Moreover,
in the current situation,
whether for Uncle Jingdong
or the Li family,
pulling it off together matters more
than the result.
So, for this Tribute Ink selection,
our Li family must participate,
and we must use the ink
made by Uncle Jingdong.
Only in this way
can our Li family
really get over it and move on.
And the hearts of the Li family
can start beating again.
I see.
Looks like you are
more insightful than I am.
But what about you?
You invested in our Li Ink
to secure military funds for Marshal Qi.
But this time,
no one knows
who will win the Tribute Ink right.
Aren't you afraid?
It's okay.
It's the same if Chen Ink is chosen.
No, no.
Don't get me wrong. I didn't mean that.
I heard it clearly.
That's exactly what you meant.
You mean
our Li Ink is not as good as Chen Ink.
In that case,
why don't you
withdraw your shares from Li Ink
and invest all the money in Chen Ink?
No, no.
Do not misunderstand me.
A gentleman's word is his bond.
And I've said before,
it doesn't matter
even if you don't participate,
because what I value is you, Zhen.
Let me see.
So this is what a gentleman looks like?
Then take a closer look.
A gentleman looks exactly like me.
Zhen,
it's still not too late
to change the ink now.
Uncle Jingdong,
do you think
there is a problem with this ink?
Our ink
is of excellent quality.
But the only thing special about it is
its deep black color.
It's nowhere as good
as the Chen family's lacquer-soot ink.
Let's change it to your Fu Jin Ink.
Today, Tian Benchang was praising
the Chen Ink and belittling the Li Ink.
He just attempted
to dampen our Li family's morale.
Ignore him.
But what he said is true.
Uncle Jingdong,
my Fu Jin Ink is medicinal ink.
Let's not mention
whether it complies with the rules
for the Tribute Ink selection.
Even if we submit it for the selection,
it might not win.
But your pine soot ink
is black enough,
marking the original intention
of ink-making,
completing the simplest thing
to the extreme extent.
It's the most suitable
for the Ink Tribute selection.
Do you still remember
the ink you and my father
made together for the first time?
Jingfu,
[Young Li Jingdong]
what's so special about this ink of ours?
Its color is black enough.
[Young Li Jingfu]
Do you still remember when we went to ask
the scholars and tutors in the studies
along the Xuefu Street,
as well as the shopkeeper
of Sibao Restaurant on Sibao Street?
Yes, I do.
The students in the studies said
that normally, when they used ink,
it faded as they wrote.
They always had to distract themselves
to grind more,
which affected their concentration.
The shopkeeper said
he rarely used ink on Xuan paper.
He often just jotted things down
on scratch paper.
When in a hurry,
he even wrote on his palms or arms.
So, ink needs to be black enough
to be useful.
Why did I forget?
It turns out that this idea was
planted in my head long ago
by Jingfu.
This ink
carries my father's original intention,
your persistence,
the techniques my grandfather taught me,
and the spirit passed down
through generations of Li Ink—
embrace simplicity and benefit the world.
But my Fu Jin Ink
can only heal the body,
while your pine soot ink
represents the unity
of the entire Li family.
Furthermore, it's the supreme ink
that Li Ink can present for now.
It's perfect
for the Tribute Ink selection.
Uncle Jingdong, you made this ink.
Please give it a name.
Zhen,
you should be the one
naming this ink,
because you are the most qualified.
Okay.
"Origin Ink."
Good.